http://www.copanational.org/en/privacy-policy/

GROUNDED
Flashpass (eAPIS)
your email
A password will be e-mailed to you.
GROUNDED
Flashpass (eAPIS)
Introduction
The Canadian Owners and Pilots Association is committed to respecting your privacy and recognizes your need for appropriate protection and management of any personal information you share with us. Personal information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including but not limited to a first and last name, a home or other physical address and an e-mail address or other contact information, whether at work or at home. COPA has established this Online Privacy Policy so that you can understand the care with which we intend to treat your personal information and to comply with the requirements set out in the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act of Canada and Canada’s Anti-Spam Legislation. We want you to know why we need your personal information, how the confidentiality of this information is protected, what information about you is recorded, and how we intend to use the information.
Accountability
COPA is responsible for your personal information that is under our control. We have appointed a Privacy Coordinator who is accountable for COPA’s compliance with this Privacy Policy. Our entire staff is trained in the organization’s policies related to privacy. Specifically, we do not provide any personal information to anyone without the consent of the individual as explained below.
Identifying Purposes
Personal information collected and retained by COPA is comprised of any or all of name, mail and email address, and telephone and facsimile numbers. Additional information is collected regarding flight training, aircraft ownership and date of birth to compile our own statistics on our members so we can determine how best to serve them. We do not sell our lists of personal information.
The information is used to conduct regular mailings to our members, in the form of the monthly newspaper and periodic notices of membership renewal status.
We currently share member contact information with trusted COPA members on an area specific basis so that they can recruit members for our COPA Flights**.
Your name, mail and email addresses and telephone number may also be transmitted to trusted third-party partners in order to inform you of products and services that our COPA partners offer and that we believe may interest you and in many cases benefit COPA through contributions made to COPA by the partners
Opting Out
If you DO NOT wish to be contacted by one of our third-party partners, please either update your membership profile and check the box marked “I do not wish to receive any solicitations from third parties” or advise the privacy coordinator 613-236-4901 or copa@copanational.org. Our COPA partners are required to have a policy in place that complies with the requirements of applicable federal or provincial privacy legislation in Canada for the Protection of personal information and they must sign a written agreement with COPA that limits their use of your personal information collected by COPA.
Consent
By being a member of COPA, you are giving COPA your consent to obtain and use your personal information, in compliance with federal legislation and this policy, whether obtained orally, by completion of the membership application, from an email or from your membership profile that you have created or updated in our online membership database.
Access/Accuracy
We do our best to keep our records accurate and up-to-date, but we need your help in making sure your personal information is correct in our membership system. Please update your profile whenever your information changes or notify us of any changes or corrections at 613-236-4901.
Safeguards
All member information in the COPA database system is encrypted and the database is password protected.  COPA will store personal information using hard copy and/or electronic means in such a way as to prevent unauthorized collection, access, use, disclosure or disposal of the personal information. Employees who have access to this information are familiar with our Privacy Policy. We may disclose personal information in responding to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal processes but only in accordance with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act of Canada. We also may choose to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may collect and possibly share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law.
Operating Principles
All questions related to the interpretation and application of this policy should be directed to the reception email copa@copanational.org or telephone 613-236-4901.
**Best Practices
In order to safeguard COPA member contact information, members who are given access to personal information for the purpose of recruiting for our COPA Flights are advised to use the BCC field when sending out emails.
© 2020 COPA - Canadian Owners and Pilots Association, 75 Albert Street, Suite 903, Ottawa, Ontario, K1P 5E7 | Tel: 613.236.4901 | Fax: 613.236.8646Contact us: copa@copanational.org
